The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Fifth Episode
The Monsters of the Three Vallies
Are you saying this rose is poisonous?
Yes, indeed. My wife pricked her finger on a thorn...
...and then she danced for three days until she died from it. Poor little wife!
And how is it there are two coffins?
Sir, my son is in the other.
The only antidote to the rose's poison...
...is an herb found in the Three Valleys...
...and my son had gone right down there to look for this herb!
He had the courage to go there?!
I heard that there are monsters in the Three Valleys!
Yes, he was surprised by one of them at the entrance to the first valley.
The monster wounded him and then...
Sapphire!
Don't you know that roses have thorns?
Be careful!
Good morning, mother!
I picked it for you!
Every morning you give me a rose. How sweet you are!
I will give you one every morning until your birthday!
What color do you want tomorrow?
- I would like a red rose.
- I will bring it to you!
- Be careful!
- Don't worry, mom!
It's adorable!
A red rose, huh?
No one in sight! Good!
Let's get rid of all the red roses!
And now...
And now... I will leave in the rose
garden only this one, in plain sight!
It's the only one and
Sapphire cannot help but pick it.
But this one is poisoned..
.
What a beautiful morning! I will go
immediately to pick a rose for my mother!
Hooray!
- Look at that squirrel!
- Let's play a trick on it!
Now I'll show you!
Look! Sapphire is down there!
These are the last moments of
happiness for you, Prince Sapphire!
You will die as soon as you
touch a thorn of the red rose!
- What a magnificent rose!
- No, wait!
Don't touch it!
Don't pick it, Prince!
How cute!
Aren't you tired?
Don't fly away! Wait!
Wait, please!
Let's play together!
Please, little birds! Listen to me!
This morning I want to
pick it myself for Sapphire.
What?! Stop! No!
What is wrong, Baron Nylon,
that you look at me this way?
How are you, Queen?
A strange energy
compels me to dance!
Good heavens! Sapphire was supposed to prick
herself and the Queen pricked herself instead!
What will happen now? That poison
takes effect immediately and is deadly!
Help me stop!
Please!
I beg you, do something!
I can't stop anymore! Help!
- What is the matter?
- My feet are dragging me!
I understand: she pricked
herself with a poisonous flower!
What a tragedy!
Mother! Tell me, what is wrong with you?
Damn it! I didn't expect it
to be the Queen herself...
...to prick herself
with that poisonous rose!
What are you saying?
She will only live for three days?!
Yes, Prince.
We are dismayed.
- Her fever is too high.
- It will take her straight to the grave.
Courtiers!
- Help!
- Mother!
Alas!
Is there a medicine to cure her?
The only remedy is to put
a specific herb on the wounds.
Quick, go gather
this herb and bring it here!
I am sorry, Prince, but the herb
grows in the Three Valleys...
...and whoever went down there
has never returned.
It wouldn't happen to be that place where rumors
say some monsters live?
Exactly, that's the one!
I will order someone
to go there immediately!
- I order you to go there!
- But I'm afraid!
Coward! Are you afraid of monsters?
Then, you go!
You know, Prince,
my wife is sick.
- And you? - I have children!
If I die, what will become of them?
- You!
- I don't feel very well.
Cowards! Alright,
then I will go myself!
Magnificent! I still get
what I was hoping for!
If Sapphire goes down there, she
will be devoured by the monsters!
We cannot allow anything to
happen to the Crown Prince!
- I will go!
- Wait, Your Highness!
Let a faithful
General of yours...
...go there at
the risk of his life!
Today's young soldiers
are nothing but weaklings!
I am forced to go myself!
- Sapphire!
- May heaven protect you!
Sapphire! Is it true that the Queen
pricked herself with a poisonous rose?
Yes! And now I'm going to the Three Valleys
to pick the herb that will cure her!
Sapphire, wait!
What? Sapphire went alone?!
But it's dangerous!
Nylon, immediately send
some soldiers to help him...
...and choose the strongest!
- Yes, yes, Sire!
Instead, I sent
the weakest soldiers!
Good, Opal.
That's the florist! I recognize him!
What is he doing in this place?
I injured my leg
and I can no longer walk.
It's the fault of that cursed monster!
Were you attacked by the monster?!
No, I fell on the rocks.
I came here to try
to avenge my son's death.
Injured like that, you won't succeed.
Don't worry, I will avenge you!
Take this waterskin of water,
Highness! It will help you!
- What should I do with it?
- Legend says...
...that the monster of the first valley
must be confronted...
.With water, not with the sword
Damn, I suffer from vertigo!
They are tongues of fire!
What is it?
Courage! Let's go!
Damned monster!
Take this!
It didn't do anything to me!
Take that!
I can't hurt it!
Damn it!
Help! Let me go!
Help!
- Hey, look over there!
- He's already taken the Prince!
Yes, he's got him!
- He saw us!
- Let's run!
Don't run away! Wait!
Come back! Help me!
It's so hot! Good
heavens, I'm burning!
The monster of the first
valley must be faced...
...with water, not
with the sword!
Right, water! I'll
splash it with this!
Incredible! The
water is killing it!
Something came out of its mouth!
The first day is about to
end. I only have two days...
...before my mother dies
exhausted, poisoned by the venom.
I must get past the other
two monsters. I must hurry!
I'll take this with me.
It will give me light!
Sapphire, dear!
Where are you, my little one?
I would like to see you before I die.
- Poor Queen!
- She will still live...
..only two days!
Poor Queen!
Who knows if Sapphire will make it...
The temperature is dropping.
But they are icicles!
I'm starting to feel cold.
Thank goodness I have the fire, otherwise
I would risk freezing to death.
I'm sleepy, but I must try
not to fall asleep.
My time has never been
so precious!
What is happening to me?
Why am I so sleepy?
A day and a half has already passed!
If Sapphire doesn't return by tomorrow,
- my dear wife will die!
- Sapphire will be killed by the monsters.
Where could Sapphire be?
In the second valley?
Do you know where the Three Valleys are?
Will you take me there, dear friends?
Hooray!
I fell asleep
and it's past noon!
It's the monster of the second valley!
Take this! Go back!
Sapphire!
It's too tight!
My sword!
Just a little more effort!
Oh, no! I'm finished!
I'm coming, Sapphire!
- Tink, give me the fire!
- Take it!
Thanks, Tink!
Take this, monster!
You managed to defeat it!
But I still have to get past
the last monster,
the one in the third valley.
Let's hurry!
What do you say, great eagle?
Take a little piece
of the monster's tail?
Do you really think
it could be useful to us?
Alright!
Damn, it's so cold!
It's colder than ice!
I'll put it in my sword's scabbard.
Let's go, now!
- Thank you, great eagle!
- Goodbye, friend!
Goodbye! Goodbye!
- Do you want to come with us?
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
I wonder what
the monster of the third valley will be like.
- Sapphire, did you see?
- They have no way out!
- Do you see that grass over there?
- It must be the herb we are looking for!
How will we reach it?
Let's cross the swamp!
- But it's terrifying!
- We have no choice
Let's see how deep
this muddy water is.
We have to get to the
grass! We can't stay here!
The two of us could make it all
the way down there, don't you think?
Would you two like to go
to get the grass?
Do you feel up to
crossing the swamp?
- Yes, yes, of course!
- Thank you, little birds!
Watch out! These are the
monsters of the third valley!
Terrifying!
I must reach that grass!
What?!
The sword!
- Come on, Tink!
- Sapphire, help!
Please save me, Sapphire! Help!
Hang on, Tink! I will save you!
I can't do it! The water
is too cold for me!
I will use the little piece of
the tail of the ice monster!
They are freezing!
They have frozen!
Damn, how cold
this icy water is!
I can't stop! Tink!
Here I am!
We'd better skate!
We'll move faster!
This will be enough!
Let's go back home!
Good heavens,
today is the third day!
We must be back at the
palace before the sun sets.
Quick, let's run!
We won't make it!
We can ask the robins to
bring the herb to the castle!
Right! Little friends, do you
feel up to flying to the castle?
Yes! Yes!
Here! Pour the herb juice
on the Queen's wound! Got it?
Yes!
Please! The life of my
mother depends on you!
Sapphire will not return.
Oh, Lord, please!
Let my wife be saved!
Is there at least some hope?
Why are you all standing
petrified staring at me?
What?! You're alive?
What did you say, Nylon?
I was saying that he returned safe
and sound with the herb, that bastard...!
Our dear Prince!
He's not dead, damn him! I'm
going crazy! I'll never get rid of him!
But I must succeed! I must
succeed! I must! I must!
Did you see? He must have gone
crazy with joy over your recovery.
- Hooray!
- Long live the Queen!
- Did you make it in time?
- Yes, the Queen is safe!
- What a relief!
- We made it, mom!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP